原作者名：Scott Manley
视频来源：youtu.be/QYdSdawgMrw
原视频发布日期：20200703
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
你好 我是Scott Manley
Hello, it's Scott Manley here.
应该是指美国国庆节假期
从假期回来 我在北加州的普鲁马斯森林露营
Back from vacation where I was camping in the Plumas forests of Northern California
无法上网 基本失联
Out of touch unable to get internet.
没有手机信号或任何东西 所以关于我在做什么 我不能说很多
There was no cell phone signal or anything so I couldn't talk very much about what I was doing.
但我意识到 这也许是最后一年了 在这一年里 这种隔离是可能的
But I sort of realized that this is maybe the last year where that kind of isolation is possible.
因为当然 我们有像Starlink和OneWeb这样的东西出现了
Because we of course have things like Starlink and OneWeb coming along
它可以提供持续的或者说是全球范围内的高带宽互联网的可用性
which could provide constant or a availability of high bandwidth internet all over the world.
所以我觉得很有意思的是 在我回来的当天 我们就收到了关于OneWeb的消息
So I think it's interesting that the day that I came back we had this news about OneWeb
所以OneWeb你可能不知道 它就像Starlink一样 但是Starlink我们就熟悉得多
and so OneWeb you may not know. It's like Starlink, which we should probably heard more about.
但OneWeb的目标是利用低地球轨道上的卫星群提供全球互联网
But OneWeb of aim to provide worldwide internet using a constellation of satellites in low Earth orbit.
与Starlink不同 他们使用的卫星较少
Unlike Starlink they use fewer satellites
但他们卫星的轨道是在1200公里处 而不是Starlink的550公里
but their orbits are at 1200 kilometers instead of Starlink's 550 kilometers.
OneWeb卫星的质量略低
OneWeb satellites are slightly lower mass.
它们运行在较高倾角的轨道上 所以它们覆盖了更多的北极地区
They operate higher inclination orbit so they cover more of the Arctic
而他们到目前为止已经从不同的客户那里获得了34亿美元的投资
and they have had so far something like 3.4 billion dollars of investment from various customers.
而他们正在寻找更多的投资 来继续他们的发射时间表
And they were looking for more to continue their launch schedule.
当软银少给OneWeb钱时 当然软银是OneWeb的主要的投资者之一
When Softbank, one of the major investors got cold feet in part
因为新冠疫情危机导致了市场的崩溃
because the COVID crisis caused a crash in the markets
这意味着很多他们期望获得的资金 很多流动资金都蒸发了
that meant a lot of the money they were expecting to have access to, a lot of the liquidity evaporated.
所以OneWeb无法获得资金 他们不得不宣布破产
And so OneWeb wasn't able to get funding and they had to declare chapter 11 bankruptcy.
但这并不是公司的结束
But that isn't the end of the company.
这只是保护他们免受债权人的清算 这样他们就可以进行重组并可能找到一个买家
That just merely gives them protection from creditors so they can restructure and possibly find a buyer
所以在过去的几个月里 他们一直在寻找买家
so for the last few months they have been looking for buyers.
他们已经削减了他们的员工 从差不多550人下降到70人左右
They've cut down their employees from something like 550 down to 70 or so.
只是保持足够的人来让公司和卫星运转
Just enough people to keep the lights on and keep the satellites in orbit.
管理地面基站
Manage the base stations.
确保现有的投资继续保持在良好的状态 以满足任何可能的买家
Make sure that the existing investments continue to be in good condition for any possible buyers.
当然 他们还雇佣了一群人
And of course they employ a bunch of people
以确保对潜在的买家进行一定的宣传 并做好所有的法律文书工作
to make sure that the potential buyers know what they're getting and do all the legal paperwork.
所以已经有一堆买家在寻求这个机会
So there's been a bunch of people looking at this.
就像我听说某时亚马逊有过这个尝试
Like I heard the Amazon was looking at one point
还有另一个运营商Telesat也是这样 (尽管)它已经有了近地轨道星座卫星的计划
and another operator Telesat who they've their own proposal for a LEO constellation.
某时他们也在尝试
They were looking at some point
但也许他们感兴趣的只是无线电或者说电磁波的频谱分配
but maybe they were interested just in the spectrum allocations that in the electromagnetic spectrum.
也有一些□□的公司对此感兴趣
And there were a couple of □□□□□□□ companies who were interested
但他们肯定没机会了
but they were never gonna win
当然 因为OneWeb是一家美国公司 而美国对此仍然会有规定
because of course it's a US company and while US would still have rules
他们有权拒绝 比方说
they would have you know right of refusal let's say.
他们将能够镇压压制任何交易
They would be able to squash any deal
而这很有可能发生 因为这将涉及到卫星技术和□□公司
and that was very likely to happen since it would involve satellite technology and □□□□□□□ companies.
今天 赢家揭晓了 那就是英国政府
The winner was revealed today and that was the British government
与一家名为Bharti Global的公司合作
in collaboration with a company called Bharti Global
是一家位于印度的大型电信运营商
who are a large telecommunications operator based in India.
他们经营着世界上最大的手机网络
They operate the world's largest cellphone network.
英国政府在网站上说的那些
The UK's government they talk about on their site
以及关于这是投资未来的新闻稿
and the press release about how this is an investment in future
以及英国在近地轨道通信方面的投资 还有英国人的工作和技术方面的投资
and your British investment in low-earth orbit communications and British jobs and technical stuff.
然而这可能是交易的一部分
And yet that might be part of the deal.
但另一方面 也有一些暗示
But on the other hand there are suggestions
这也是在研究英国对伽利略投资的可能替代品
that this is also looking at the possible replacement for a Britain's investment in Galileo.
那么 伽利略是欧洲版的GPS或者说格洛纳斯
So Galileo is the European version of GPS or Glonass.
需要注意的是 欧空局和欧盟没有直接的隶属关系 但他们都受各自参与国的管辖
它是由欧盟国家开发的 是欧洲和欧洲空间局的一部分
It was developed by EU countries as part of the European and part of the European Space Agency.
英国公司在开发伽利略规格上做了大量工作
British companies worked a great deal on developing the Galileo spec
但是 退欧成真使得所有的工作都毁于一旦
but as soon as Brexit became a thing, all that work disappeared.
很多参与相关工作的人真的就是收拾东西走人 去了欧洲大陆
And many of the actual people that had worked on literally picked up and went to continental Europe
他们可以在那里继续工作 因为他们不能在英国做了
where they could continue working on this since they couldn't do it in the UK anymore.
那么那个暗示是 也许英国可以用这个
So the suggestion is that maybe we could use maybe Britain could use this
来替代伽利略系统 或者说用于自己的卫星导航网络
instead of Galileo or for its own sort of private navigation Network
而这一点 嗯 值得商榷
And that's hmmm that's sort of questionable.
那么 GPS 伽利略 格洛纳斯 他们都使用L波段信号 也就是1到2GHz的频段范围
So GPS, Galileo, Glonass they all use L band signals and 1 to 2 gigahertz range
这意味着它们可以使用全向天线 并可以连接到多个卫星
which means they can use a omnidirectional antenna and can connect to multiple satellites
而OneWeb卫星是在Ku波段运行 从12到18GHz
whereas the OneWeb satellites are they are operating in the Ku band which runs from 12 to 18 gigahertz
而这些信号主要是定向的 所以你需要一个天线
and these signals are largely directional so you need an antenna
它能够在一定角度范围内定位
which is able to localize to within a certain angular area.
卫星使用Ku波段
The satellites use the Ku band
因为某种程度上它是一种门槛 你可以用小的抛物面天线来得到相对较好的天线范围
because it's sort of the threshold at which you can have a small parabolic dish and get relatively good localization.
你的卫星电视来自于地球静止轨道
Your satellite TV comes from geostationary orbit
那么需要一定的方向性 才能在地球静止轨道上部署多个卫星
so you want some directionality so you can have multiple satellites in geostationary orbit
不然它们就会互相干扰
and not have them interfere with each other.
所以 如果OneWeb要把卫星转交给英国政府来添加定位功能的话
So if they were to consider switching this over to you to become sort of or at least adding the capability.
他们就需要增加超稳定(准时)的原子钟
They would need to add ultra stable atomic clocks.
他们需要增加在这些频段范围内广播的能力 这样他们就可以和现有的芯片通信
They would need to add the ability to broadcast in these band ranges so that they could talk to existing chips.
你知道人们在硬件处理器上处理GPS和格洛纳斯或者其他的导航系统的信号
You know people that make the processors on the hardware that handle GPS and Glonass and everything.
几乎所有的操作原理都是一样的
The pretty much all operating on the same principle.
他们得到的是轨道元素 位置数据和时间
They're getting orbital elements, positional data and a time.
他们利用这些多源数据来进行四元方程组的计算
And they use all this with multiple sources to do quadrilateral
也就是通过好几颗远距离的卫星
where you basically have multiple distances to targets
来得知自己在地球表面的位置 精度几米之内
and you figure out where you are on the surface of the earth to within a few meters
甚至可能是更高的精度 一旦真的知道(影响精度的因素)
or possibly even higher precision once you really know what's going on.
所以 是的 如果英国想把这个变成一个定位系统
So yeah if Britain wanted to turn this into a geolocation system,
他们将不得不修改卫星 并添加一些额外的硬件来做到这一点
they would have to modify the satellites and add some extra hardware to do this.
但是 如果他们想用它来为英国带来工作机会等等
But if they want to use it to bring jobs back to the UK and all that.
那么 现在的问题是 这十亿美元中的很多都将用于OneWeb
Well, the problem with this right now is that a lot of that billion dollars that's going to the OneWeb,
已经讲过了 因为有现有的债务需要偿还
has already been spoken for because there are existing debts to be paid.
例如 阿丽亚娜空间公司一直在处理所有卫星的发射工作
For example Arianespace has been handling the launch of all the satellites
而卫星发射很多都已经预付了费用
and many these people satellite launches have already been paid in advance.
可能是指2020年3月21日那次发射
6天后OneWeb就申请破产
事实上在OneWeb破产之后 他们就继续用联盟号火箭进行发射 上面有34颗卫星
Indeed after OneWeb went bankrupt, they proceeded ahead with a launch on a Soyuz with 34 satellites on.
阿丽亚娜空间公司到目前为止已经进行了三次发射 都是用联盟火箭
Arianespace has handled three launches so far all in Soyuz launchers.
我想 最后三次发射 他们将改用阿丽亚娜6
They're gonna switch to Ariane 6 I believe for the last three
但会有20多个联盟号进行发射
but there's like 20 odd Soyuz launches that are gonna happen.
阿丽亚娜空间公司预计 仅联盟号的发射 就会有2.82亿美元的收入
Arianespace is expecting another 282 million dollars just for the Soyuz launches
如果他们想继续下去 就必须马上支付
and that'll have to be paid out pretty much right away if they want to continue.
这个卫星制造 是和空中客车的合资企业
This satellite manufacturing, that is a joint venture with airbus.
同样 它真的也不在英国
Again it's not really in Britain.
实际上 他们在佛罗里达州的工厂建造这些卫星
It's actually the factory where they're building these is in Florida.
那么 也可以假设 他们不要这种合作关系了 重建一个新的
So hypothetically yes they could take this partnership, reconstruct it.
试着把它搬到英国去 但这也许不可能
Try to move it to the UK but that might not be possible.
可能会有卫星技术无法出口
There might be satellite technology which isn't available for an export
而他们必须为此获得例外 你猜怎么着
and they would have to get an exception for that and guess what.
美国不可能给英国破例
The US isn't likely to give the UK an exception
让他们把工作机会从佛罗里达州转移到英国去
to let them take jobs out of Florida and to move them to the UK.
即使如此 他们也在和星链进行竞争
And even then they're in a race with Starlink.
对吧？他们已经把70码的卫星运到那里去了
Right? They've got to get 70-yard satellites up there already.
大部分卫星现在都在600公里的轨道上呢
Most of them sitting in 600 kilometer parking orbits right now.
星链在上面有300颗卫星 他们的网络发展得很快
Starlink has like 300 satellites up there and they're growing their network very quickly.
所以 如果你有一个专门生产这些卫星的工厂的话
So if you've got a factory that's designed to churn out these satellites
而你却说要把它移到别的地方去
and you then to say to move it elsewhere.
这是要去减缓你的生产 下来 这可能不是你想要做的
That's gonna slow your production down and that might not be what you want to do.
所以从长远来看 我不知道这对英国到底有什么好处
So I'm not sure how this really works for the UK in the long run.
Scott: 我不是针对谁，我是说在座的脱欧派都是辣鸡.jpg
我不是说这必然是很蠢的
I'm not saying as automatically stupid by any means.
我是指已经有一些可笑而愚蠢的交易发生在这后脱欧时代的英国
I mean there have been some ridiculously stupid deals made in post Brexit that Britain.
主要是由于赤裸裸的□□裙带关系和腐败
Largely thanks to you know straight-up □□□□□□□□□□ cronyism and corruption.
应该是这个www.ft.com/content/f0dd3024-2c4d-11e9-ba00-0251022932c8
你知道 然后著名的案例是某个公司 应该提供渡轮服务
You know and then famous case being the company that was supposed to deliver ferry services
但他们在航运方面没有任何记录
but they didn't have any track record with shipping.
主要是因为他们没有任何船只
Largely because they didn't own any ships.
是啊 还没到那种程度
Yeah, it's not quite at that level.
它甚至不一定是愚蠢的
It's not even necessarily stupid.
这实际上可能会有很好的效果
This could actually work out very well.
老实说 我们还不知道这笔交易是如何安排的
We don't honestly know how this deal is gonna be structured.
它还没有得到适当的批准 而这将发生在未来几周
It has yet to be properly approved that'll happen over the coming weeks.
但我可以想象 如果这次交易成功了
But I would imagine that if this comes through
我们将看到的是 他们将再次在佛罗里达开动工厂
what we'll see is they'll spin up the factory again in Florida.
他们将为网络的其他部分建造卫星 并继续发射火箭
They'll build out to the satellites for the rest of the network and they'll continue to launch rockets.
顺便说一句 阿丽亚娜空间公司提供的发射能力 是另一个有趣的数据点
Incidently Arianespace providing the launch capabilities is another interesting data point here
因为前两次发射都是在南美的库鲁进行的
because the first two launches happened out of Kourou in South America.
阿丽亚娜空间公司的主要发射场之一就在那里
That's where Arianespace has one of their major launch sites.
但在第三次发射中 他们将发射地点移到了哈萨克斯坦的拜科努尔
But for the third launch they moved it to Baikonur in Kazakhstan
所以是俄罗斯的火箭从哈萨克斯坦发射出去的
so it was a Russian rocket launching out of Kazakhstan.
很明显 把卫星用飞机运到那个发射场并整合起来(再发射)更有意义
Obviously it makes more sense just to fly the satellites up to that launch site and integrate them.
它们毕竟是要进入极地轨道的
They are after all they're going to polar orbit.
而库鲁的低纬度在这种情况下并不能给你带来任何优势
And the lower latitudes of Kourou doesn't give you any advantage in that case.
也许有一种可能性 他们认为他们可能会从英国的运载火箭上发射几颗OneWeb卫星
Maybe there's a possibility that they see they might launch a few OneWeb satellites from British launch vehicles
因为我们刚刚得到了萨瑟兰太空港的批准
because we've just got the Sutherland Spaceport has been approved.
太空女孩是指空射维珍轨道的火箭LauncherOne的载机，经改装过的波音747
维珍轨道公司已经批准发射设备 一个太空女孩 他们的发射载具 从康沃尔起飞
A Virgin Orbit have approved to launch hardware, a Cosmic Girl their launch vehicle out of Cornwall.
是的 我是指 我想他们可以用这些火箭从这些地方发射一些卫星
So yeah I mean I guess they could launch some satellites on these vehicles out of these locations
但他们能用联盟号发射34枚
but it they're able to launch 34 on a Soyuz.
他们也许(只)能用维珍轨道公司的火箭发射3枚
They might be able to launch three on Virgin Orbits launcher.
也许在其他一些火箭上也能发射两个 比如Orbex
Maybe two on some of the other launchers such as Orbex.
我相信有一个火箭正试图从苏格兰北部发射
I believe is one launcher that's trying to launch out of out of the north of Scotland.
因此 如果这是一个给英国发射供应商提供携带有效载荷的机会
So if this was an opportunity to give British launch providers payloads to carry,
它将在很大程度上是象征性的 不一定是一个很好的商业举措
it would largely be symbolic and not necessarily a good business move.
所以是的 搞咩啊
So yeah I don't know where this is going.
但我确实已经绞尽脑汁地去预测未来半年左右与之相关的事情了
But this is my sort of brain dump on what I think might be relevant in the next six months or so.
我认为无论如何OneWeb也不太可能就此消亡
I don't think OneWeb is ruled out by any means
那么OneWeb的实际定位是为极点提供服务
so what OneWeb are actually positioning themselves provide service to the poles.
而星链目前还没有发射任何能覆盖极点的卫星
Whereas Starlink hasn't launched any satellites that give pole coverage just yet.
所以OneWeb完全有可能在那里开辟出一个市场 然后在获得客户后向南发展
So it's entirely likely that OneWeb can carve out a niche there and then move south as they get customers.
当然 Starlink的优势在于他们发射了更多的卫星
Starlink of course has the advantage that they're launching more satellites.
而且他们拥有发射系统 所以他们的成本可能更低？
And they own the launch system so their costs are probably lower?
当然我们其实不知道 因为这都是超级机密
Of course we don't actually know because it's all super-secret.
但是在发射方面 SpaceX给自己的待遇相当不错 这似乎是符合逻辑的
But it would be seem logical that SpaceX is giving themselves a pretty good deal when it comes to launches.
所以啊 OneWeb 现在是英国政府的财产
So yeah OneWeb, now property of the UK government
Scott已经入籍美国，但按照英国的国籍法，他仍保有英国国籍 twitter.com/DJSnM/status/1275438429933690880
我想 这意味着我拥有它的一部分 以某种方式在非常非常小的方式
which means I guess I own part of it somehow in very some very small way.
我是Scott Manley 切记 注意飞行安全
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.